Woodbridge, VA (Open to relocation) kaushikmondal1717@gmail.com (571) 598-6952

Kaushik Mondal

Software Engineer

kaushikm.com (Portfolio) github.com/kaushikkm17 linkedin.com/in/kaushikdev

Software engineer with education in psychology and professional experience building, testing, and deploying full stack web apps using Python's Django/PostgreSQL stack and JavaScript's MERN stack. Previously worked in the mental health field from which I bring skills of communication and interpersonal skills, teamwork, research and data analysis.

Skills

Frontend: HTML/CSS, TypeScript, React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass, Tailwind, JavaScript, EJS **Backend:** Java, Python, Django, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, REST API

Devops: Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, AWS S3 || Testing: Jest || Version Control: Git

Project Management: Agile, Scrum, SDLC || **OS:** Linux, MacOS, Windows **Other:** Photoshop, Figma, Trello, Slack, Visual Studio, CLI, Postman, Heroku

Work Experience

Software Engineer Apprentice, General Assembly

Nov. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Created 5 projects in a software engineering immersive program working 70+ hours each week for 12 weeks learning from industry professionals using the MERN stack and Django/PostgreSQL stack
 - *Career Tracker* Developed an app for job searchers that helps keep track of things like connections made, skills to learn, current tasks, etc. It is built using Django/PostgreSQL, styled with Tailwind, deployed to Heroku, and is able to authenticate and authorize users using Django's built in authentication.
 - *Techfolio* Collaborated with 3 other developers to build a platform for people in tech to display their technical portfolio including projects, skills, interests, etc. It used the MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, git team workflow, and Google Firebase for user login and is deployed on Heroku.
 - *Finch Collector* Developed an app where a user can add finches, their feeding schedule, and toys they play with using Django and PostgreSQL in a full CRUD app using Django for authentication and AWS S3.
 - *Anime Generator* Created an app that displays an anime character or anime that retrieves the data from the Kitsu API and displays it to the DOM. Technologies used include jQuery, HTML, CSS, and Google Fonts.

Research Assistant, George Mason University Dept. of Psychology

Mar. 2020 - Oct. 2021

- Fairfax, VA
- Collaborated with fellow researchers to execute fMRI studies and meticulously analyzed the data obtained from participants
- Conducted extensive research, sourced and analyzed relevant articles, and effectively communicated findings to the lead researcher.
- Assisted in the study planning process by contributing to the development of methods, and provided thorough proofreading support for the final paper.

Education

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp, *General Assembly* **Bachelor of Science in Psychology,** *George Mason University*

Nov. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Sept. 2018 - May. 2022